

ABOUT ME

I am a **UX/UI designer** who is passionate about creating efficient, simple and meaningful experiences. My education in **architecture** and my work experience **as a software tester** have taught me how to use design thinking and user research to solve complex problems. I also know how to evaluate the performance and quality of **digital products** and **communicate** with the **development team** to provide effective feedback and suggestions.

EXPERIENCES

Product Designer | *ThisApp | Oct 2022 - Present

Redesigned an app and website for budget management and spreading cryptocurrencies.

- Simplifying the concepts led to the prototype zero-based budgeting tool.
- Simplified financial concepts and workflows made the program more accessible and user-friendly.
- Collaborated with engineers to launch new features that increased user satisfaction and revenue.
- Material Design guidelines 2 and 3 were utilized to ensure a consistent and modern user experience across the app and website.
- A modern and visually appealing user interface was designed that followed Apple's strict guidelines for app acceptance into the App Store, enabling ThisApp Budget to expand its user base to iOS users.

UX/UI Designer | Ecokiddo - UXLand School | May 2023 - Jul 2023

Designed an online store for selling children's sustainable clothes up to eight years old.

- Working in multidisciplinary teams, understanding the importance of effective communication, time management, lead challenging situations and teamwork.
- I realized that designing is not just about my own perspective, but about putting the users' needs first. As a result, I am able to approach problem solving from various perspectives.
- I understand how important it is for a project to stick to design principles.

UX/UI Designer | Ether - UXLand School | Sep 2023 - Feb 2024

Designed an app for astrology.

- A Unity-based user interface was created.
- Learning advanced UI and Thinking out of the box.
- Based on gamification.

CONTACT INFO

Email: ameneh.yazdanii@gmail.com Phone Number: +989011363274

Location: Tehran, Iran

Portfolio Linkedin

SKILLS & TOOLS

Disciplines

User Interface Design (UI) - Visual Design - Interaction Design - User Experience Design (UX) - User Research - Information Architecture (IA)

Methods

Surveys - User Interviews - Qualitative & Quantitive Research - Comparative & Competitive Analysis - Affinity Mapping - Heuristic Evaluation - Card Sorting - Persona Creation - Feature Prioritization - SWOT - A/B Testing - Usability Testing

Deliverables

Wireframes - Interactive Prototype -Responsive Design - Adaptive Design -High Fidelity Design - Journey Maps -Storyboard Scenarios - User/Task Flow -Site Maps - Visual Style Guides -UX Research Reports

Softwares

Figma - Adobe Illustrator - Adobe Photoshop - Figjam - Penpot - Miro - Unity - Microsoft Office - Canva - Ora

LANGUAGES

English Persian

EDUCATION

UX/UI Design Bootcamp

UXLand

Jan 2023 - Feb 2024

Bachelor of Architecture

University of Science and Culture OCT 2015 - Jul 2020

EXPERIENCES

UX Designer | Kish Takhfif - UXLand School | Mar 2023 - Apr 2023

Redesigned a website that offers discounts for buying tickets for various recreational activities in Kish Island, Iran.

- Focused on UX research.
- Teamwork
- Heuristic Evaluation
- Card Sorting
- prototypes
- Usability Test

UX Researcher | Ordream - UXLand School | Feb 2023 - Mar 2023

Researched a task for a website that accepts custom gold order and builds them.

- Survey
- User Interviews
- Competitive Analysis
- Persona
- Storyboard Scenarios
- User Flow
- Wireframes

Software Tester | Pendulums & Commenta | Jun 2018 - Oct 2021

Pendulums: The product is a web and mobile application for time management.

Commenta: The product is a mobile application for sharing opinions about different products.

- I was responsible for testing the functionality, usability, and performance of the product.
- used various tools and techniques to identify issues and defects.
- Collaborated with the developers and the designers to ensure the quality and reliability of the product.